Guide to the World War I Posters File [1914]-1920 PR 55-7
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Monetary Appeals, 2
  - Subseries II.3: Third Liberty Loan, 10
    - After a zepplin raid in London/"But mother had done nothing wrong, had she daddy?"/Prevent this in New York/Invest in Liberty bonds, 1917 (Folder 13)
      Weeping Father Daughter nexat to deceased mother covered with a sheet/cross on hospital bed. (black/white)
    - Fight or buy bonds/Third Liberty Loan, 1917 circa (Folder 13)
      Liberty (relatively unclad) leading the troops
    - USA bonds/Third Liberty Loan campaign/Boy Scouts of America/Weapons for liberty, 1918 (Folder 13)
      Statue of Liberty and Boy Scout with sword printed with "Be Prepared".
    - My soldier / Buy United States Government bonds/Third Liberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 13)
      mother and child saying evening prayers before bedtime/"The Lord's Prayer" revised to pray for brother gone to war
    - The big drive / For democracy/Buy 3rd Liberty Loan bonds/It's success depends on you! (Folder 13)
      arm with armband/3rd Liberty Loan on arm knocking out hun
    - Come on!/Buy more Liberty bonds, 1918 (Folder 13)
      advancing soldier with bayonet - in direct confrontation with enemy
    - "Lend him a hand" / Buy Liberty Bonds, 1918 (Folder 13)
      soldier with bayonet climbing out of trench
  - Subseries II.4: Fourth Liberty Loan, 11
    - The A.E.F. to the President: "If the folks back home fall short on the billions you need, Mr. President, call on us for the Balance. We like our pay but if we have to we can go without it. Yours for Victory, A.E.F/4th Lberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 14)
      soldier with bayonet/plus above "letter" to the president
    - Hun or home?/Buy more Liberty bonds, 1918 (Folder 14)
      Mother carrying baby/menacing Hun approaching
    - We clear the way/For your fighting dollars/Buy 4th Liberty Loan/US Government bonds, 1918 circa (Folder 14)
      sailor charging with bayonet
    - Think have you bought your limit?/Fourth Liberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 14)
      all print
    - That liberty shall not perish from the earth/Buy Liberty bonds/Fourth Liberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 14)
      Statue of Liberty/N.Y. in Flames (sepia on buff paper)
    - President Wilson's appeal for the Fourth Liberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 14)
      photo of Wilson and printed appeal
    - Wear your fourth Liberty Loan honor bulletin/4th Liberty loan bonds (Folder 14)
      flag with 4 stripes
    - Stop/Have you gone your limit in Liberty bonds?/Fighting Fourth Liberty Loan (Folder 14)
    - Subscriber/4th Liberty Loan/Subscriber (Folder 14)
    - Provide the sinews of war/Buy Liberty bonds, 1918 (Folder 14)
      Battleship at dock (on card stock, black/white)
    - Clearthe way!!/Buy bonds/Fourth Liberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 14)
      "Liberty" as a sexy babe inspiring sailors on board ship
    - Remember Belgium/Buy bonds/Fourth Liberty Bond, 1918 (Folder 14)
      Hun leading young girl away against background of flames
    - Today/Buy that Liberty Bond, 1918 (Folder 14)
      rising sun with face
    - Today/Buy that Liberty Bond, 1918 (Folder 14)
      rising sun-face
    - Beat back the Hun/With/Liberty bonds, 1918 (Folder 14)
      Hun with bloodied hands & bayonet being "puhed" off top of page by sea of Liberty Loans
    - You who are not called upon to die Subscribe to the Fourth Liberty Loan, 1918 (Folder 14)
      dead soldier on battlefield & story reped from Stars & Stripes
  - Subseries II.5: Victory (Fifth) Liberty Loan, 12
    - If you had to tell time by a Little Tin Horn / We paid their way over. We've got to pay it back / Buy Liberty Bonds, 1919 (Folder 15)
      Tin Bugle (black - white)
    - He can have my shirt now / That kid can have anything I've got I'm going to finish my job, too., 1919 (Folder 15)
      Soldier marching before bombed-out buildings (black - white)
    - "A Cold Blooded Business Proposition", 1919 (Folder 15)
      crosses on battlefield
    - "Sergeant Burr speaking, sir"/ An advertisement originated and produced for the Victory Liberty Loan by members of the American Expeditionary Force.", 1919 (Folder 15)
      soldiers on battlefield (black and white)
    - These are our decorations/The Liberty Bonds we bought that we couldn't afford/This is your last chance, and mine, to perform that service for our country and win that decoration., 1919 (Folder 15)
      Civilian With Victory Bonds/Liberty Bonds on Steps Surrounded by Wounded Soldiers (black and white)
    - "Dear Mother"/A Letter from a nineteenyear old Illinois boy to his mother back home Somewhere in France/Buy Liberty Bonds today/To your limit, 1919 circa (Folder 15)
      soldier/statue of liberty rear/image of stamp (lower left) of soldier tossing grenade - lend the way they fight - buy bonds
    - Berlin or bust!/Liberty Bonds will do it/Buy them To your limit!, 1919 (Folder 15)
      soldiers on battlefield, Germans in retreat - newspaper clipping "Germans Flee before Americans, with the Amricans Near Soissons, July 19 (5:55 AM) (black and white)
    - To the folks back home: We are finishing our job are you finishing yours? Private A.E.F./On the Rhine, 1919 (Folder 15)
      soldier with gun (black and white)
    - Remember Argonne/Chateau Thierry etc., and invest, 1919 (Folder 15)
      Athena? Guarding piles of money
    - If you at home could begin to realize how wonderful a place America seems to her exiled sons you would spare nothing to make it worhty of their dreams. Keep its honor clean and fine and unstained for them! Pay america's debts of Victory. / A. E. F., 1919-01 (Folder 15)
      Ruminating soldier / sign rear Officers / four homes (black - white)
    - Did they quit? / Let's finish the job with this Victory Liberty Loan, 1919 (Folder 15)
      One seated man, one standing and pointing to scenes of battle and war casualties (black - white)
    - For home and country / Victory Liberty Loan, 1919 (Folder 15)
      Soldier with wife and child
    - Honor roll/The following patriotic men and women in this organization have invested in the Victory Liberty Loan, 1919 (Folder 15)
      honor roll numbered 1-100/flag with V on it
    - Their unfinished work and ours / The Vicoty Liberty Loan is a call to this unfinished work Respond from your heart, 1919 (Folder 15)
      Soldiers trouping in the rain (black - white)
    - For some of us the war will never be over / Victory Liberty Loan, 1919 (Folder 15)
      A blind soldier with left arm amputated
    - And they thought we couldn't fight / Victory Liberty Loan, 1919 (Folder 15)
      soldier with helmets, bayonet, smiling against ruins and barbed wire
    - Buy the way you fought / Victory Notes, 1919 (Folder 15)
      two soldiers with mortar, bayonet, others in rear
    - The boys come home / Veterans of New York's 27th division, 20,000 strong marching through the Victory Arch in Madison Square. / Oversubscribe the Victory Loan, 1919 (Folder 15)
    - The Victory Loan Flyers / Watch for the airplane special, 1919 (Folder 15)
      planes in formation over a locamotive
    - Invest (Folder 15)
      huge V
  - Subseries II.6: Non-Pictoral Liberty Loans, 13
    - Pro Russian or Pro Pershing / Buy Liberty Bonds (Folder 16)
    - We / Came / Bought / Conquered (Folder 16)
    - 7 in 1 Give! To keep our boys clean and healthy then home (Folder 16)
    - The widow's mite behind the soldier's might / A Liberty Bond (Folder 16)
    - Don't let swindlers persuade you to part with your Liberty Bonds or War Savings Stamps (Folder 16)
    - Buy Liberty Bonds (Folder 16)
    - The United States 4% Government bond is in the Army / Do you want to save this way? / Bonds may be bought at all bureaus in camp and may be left in safe deposit here (Folder 16)
    - Invest! / V (Folder 16)
    - Make your dollars end the war / Your liberty your forefathers died for is at stake / If you can't fight your money can / Buy a Liberty Bond and Uncle Sam will do the rest., 1917 (Folder 16)
    - Honor button / Victory Liberty Loan / Every American should consider it an honor to wear this button / Carter Glass, Secretary of the Treasury (Folder 16)
    - Uneasy lies / The head which / Has no bond (Folder 16)
    - US Government / 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917 / Buy your Liberty Bond today / At any bank (Folder 16)
    - A better investment than a Liberty Bond Two Liberty Bonds (Folder 16)
    - Buy today / Buy Liberty Bonds / At any bank (Folder 16)
      Target with "Buy Liberty Bonds" as bull's eye
    - Lend! / Lend! / Double / The / Third! (Folder 16)
    - Invest in the future of America (Folder 16)
    - We own a US Government bond (Folder 16)
    - Seal your lips / Steel your hearts / Open your purses / and buy / Fighting Fourth Liberty Bonds, 1918 (Folder 16)
    - Is your name on the honor roll? / Fourth Liberty Loan (Folder 16)
    - Household / Honor emblem / Victory Liberty Loan / 100% (Folder 16)
    - V / Invest (Folder 16)
    - Subscribe / V / Victory Liberty Loans / Awarded by the United States Treasury Dept. (Folder 16)
    - Button! / Button! / Who's got the liberty button? (Folder 16)
    - Volunteer / Workers / Wanted / For the / Third / Liberty loan / April at / Local headquarters / 1400 St. Nicholas Ave (Folder 16)
    - Help protect your flag / Liberty war Loan Club / Now open for membership / subscriptions also received on regular Gov't basis / The Merchant's National Bank, New Haven, Conn (Folder 16)
    - Second Liberty Loan / $3,000,000,000 / U.S. Gov't 4% cupon Bonds / The Morris Plan C of NY / Union Square Branch 1 Union Square / Main Office 120 Broadway / Bronx office 391 East 149 Street (Folder 16)
    - Liberty / Bonds / Are / Fighting / Bonds / Buy them! (Folder 16)
    - Are you a patriot? What can you do? / Uncle Sam asks you to help by buying a US gov't 3 per cent Liberty Bond / If you do not have all the cash join the Liberty Loan Club (Folder 16)
    - I am New York and this is my creed. / New York will see it through! / Government loan organization (Folder 16)
    - Facts About Liberty Bonds / $3,000,000,000 in bonds of $50 and multiples thereof / Interest of 4% payable semiannually / guaranteed buy US gov't (Folder 16)
    - Buy early (Folder 16)
    - For home and country (Folder 16)
    - German slavery or Liberty Bonds (Folder 16)
    - A good part of the proceeds of this farm have gone into Liberty Bonds (Folder 16)
    - By the President of the United States of America / A Proclomation / Wednesday the 24th of October, as Liberty Day / Woodrow Wilson / Robert Lanning, Secretary of State, 1917 (Folder 16)
      Statue of Liberty background
    - Double the Third! (Folder 16)
    - Fight! Or buy Liberty Bonds (Folder 16)
    - Free storage of Liberty Bonds / Keep those you have and buy more (Folder 16)
    - "Victory" Liberty Loans / V / Bring 'em on we'll "Buy or Bust" (Folder 16)
    - United States Government Liberty Bons / Mean "Freedom for all Forever" / (slogan translated into 19 languages) (Folder 16)
    - *In Polish* Kup Two'j Bond Juz Dzisaij (Folder 16)
    - Buy Liberty Bonds here / U means you / S means subscribe / A means at once (Folder 16)
    - Lend! (Folder 16)
    - We have subscribed for a Liberty Bond / Have you? (Folder 16)
      eagle / flag
    - Your opportunity / Help your country. Buy your Liberty Bond from any bank or banker / TODAY (Folder 16)
  - Subseries II.7: Unidentified Liberty Loans and Miscelaneous Appeals, 14
    - She does not ask for contributions / She asks you to invest your money at 4% / in US Government Bonds (Folder 17)
      Liberty holding a 4% Liberty Loan Bond
    - Bonds which? (Folder 17)
      Uncle Sam / in one hand handcuffs labeled Prussia / other hand a Liberty Bond
    - The $3.000,000,000 punch (Folder 17)
      Uncle Sam wearing Liberty Bond posters tied arund torso punching a Hun (black - white)
    - If you can't enlist, invest! / Buy a Liberty Bond (Folder 17)
      Uncle Sam with a boynet offering a Liberty Bond
    - We sell $10 Liberty Loan Certificates / Five of these buy a $150 bond / US Government 3 % Liberty Bonds (Folder 17)
    - This is your war / Help win it by / subscribing to the / Liberty Loan / See your bank or write to Liberty Loan Committee / 108 So 4th St. (Folder 17)
      Family hovering in shadow of Prussianism
    - Help crush the menace of the seas / Buy Liberty Bonds / Buy quickly / Buy freely (Folder 17)
      Bloodied hand with knife rising from ocean
    - Remember the bond, 1918-04 (Folder 17)
      Soldier cought in barbed wire on battlefield
    - Strike now! / He's fighting for you / Buy Liberty Bonds, 1918-04-22 (Folder 17)
      soldier bayonetting Hun (black - white)
    - Your country calls / Enlist / Plow Buy bonds (Folder 17)
      Soldier, farmer, banker as unit
    - Lend to your Uncle / You have what you have because of him / Buy a Victory Note (Folder 17)
      Uncle Sam / soldier, sailor, marine / flage as his eyes, ears, mouth
    - Give / All in one hat, 1919-11-12 (Folder 17)
      Red, white, blue upturned tophat with money tumbling in
    - The Road to France He is keeping it open / The Road to Berlin He is building it / The guns that do it He is making them / But the Liberty Bond you buy It Backs them All (Folder 17)
      Busts of sailer, soldier, and munitions worker
    - All about Liberty Bonds / What are they? / Why should I buy them? / How can I buy them? / Where can I buy them? / When shall I buy them? (Folder 17)
      statue of liberty background
    - Lend as they fight / Buy more Liberty Bonds (Folder 17)
      2 soldiers, one wounded shooting pistol, one with rifle protecting him on battlefield
    - Give your share / One campaign / Instead of 60 drives / One pledge / 12 Installments / For all 1919 (Folder 17)
      Footlocker with "Minneapolis, give your share" printed on front*
    - Help fill the war chest / Humanity calls (Folder 17)
      Liberty and shower of gold coins byefore war-torn people and soldiers
    - 1919 war chest / Give your share / 60 funds / Local and war relief in one (Folder 17)
      Footlocker with "Minneapolis" on front
    - Liberty Loan / Become a patriotic bond holder / Subscribe today (Folder 17)
      Arm holding Bond of Loyalty; white house in rear
    - If you can't enlist Invest / Buy Liberty Bonds / See your bank today (Folder 17)
    - "I'd like to be there" / Do it! / Get into the fight / Buy Liberty Bonds to your utmost (Folder 17)
      Battle scene (black - white) and printed logo of man tossing grenade
    - Tired of giving? We don't know what it is to be tired / We have not made such sacrifices as the women of Belgium and France / We shall never have to if we all buy Liberty Bonds (Folder 17)
      weeping mother and child in rubble of house (black - white)
    - Ammunition! / and remember Bonds Buy Bullets!, 1918 (Folder 17)
      Soldier with machine gun, bayonet reaching out for funds
  - Subseries II.8: War Savings Stamps, 15
    - United States of America/This is to certify that ______has been appointed an authorized agent of the Treasury Department/For the year ending December 31, 1919/For the sale of/United States War Savings certificate stamps/And/United States thrift stamps (Folder 18)
      Ben Franklin
    - United States of America/Treasury Department/No/This is to certify that the ______/WarSavings Society/Of/_____is affiliated with the War Loan Organization, Savings Division, United States Treasury Department/Dated this____ day of _____ 1919. (Folder 18)
    - Your War/Savings/Pledge/Our boys make good/Their pledge/Are you keeping/Yours?/W.S.S./War savings stamps/Issued by the/United States government (Folder 18)
      Uncle Sam/Arms around soldier & civilian holding W.S.S.
    - We are buying/W.W.S./To help the/Army & Navy/Win the war (Folder 18)
      torch of Liberty on W.S.S. logo
    - My soldier/Now I lay me down to sleep/I pray the Lord my soul to keep/God bless my brother gone to war/Across the seas, in France, so far..how can you help?/Save/Buy war stamps (Folder 18)
      Mother & child saying prayers
    - For sale here/W.S.S./War savings stamps/Issued by the United States government/Also thrift stamps (Folder 18)
    - $5.00/W.S.S./For $4.12/Will cost 1 cent more/Each month after Feb. 1st, 1918/Save and buy for cash/Or installment Plan/25 cents down/25 cents anytime (Folder 18)
    - Four services you/Perform every time/You buy a war savings stamp/..Thrift and war savings stamps/"Little baby Liberty bonds"/On sale at this post (Folder 18)
    - Stamp!/Stamp!/Stamp!!!/the Boys are Marching/Buy War Savings Stamps (Folder 18)
      Soldiers with bayonets marching towards bombed - out town
    - W.S.S. Pictorial News Form A. (Folder 18)
      Miscellaneous news photos and photos of posters
    - Attention!/Complete your 1919 war/Savings certificate before/December 31/..There will be a new issue of government/Savings securities in 1920, but 1920 stamps cannot be pasted/Upon a 1919 war savings certificate/Card/Start a 1920 card on January 1st (Folder 18)
    - Fool the enemy!/The enemy's chuckling/He thinks you're going to waste/That quarter/But you're going to fool him/ You're going to buy a thrift stamp with that quarter../Thrift and war savings stamps/On sale at this post/Start buying now and get the habit (Folder 18)
    - Save /Buy /For victory./W.S.S../For sale here, 1918 circa (Folder 18)
    - W.S.S. Pictorial News (Form B) (Folder 18)
    - W.S.S. Pictorial News Form C (Folder 18)
    - W.S.S. Pictorial News (without form listing) (Folder 18)
    - Victory Loan, Pictorial News (Folder 18)
    - Save and serve/Buy W.S.S./War savings stamps, 1918 circa (Folder 18)
      U.S.S. eagle
    - Help stop this / Bury W.S.S. / and keep him out of America / National War Savings Committee / Contributed by L.E. Waterman Company (Folder 19)
      An advancing Hun trampling on dead woman
    - Systematic savings / Sensible spending / Buy W.S.S. (Folder 19)
    - Begin War Savings Today / This is your Country / Prove it! (Folder 19)
      Flying eagle
    - Your war savings pledge / Our boys make good their pledge / Are you keeping yous? (Folder 19)
      Uncle Sam with 1 arm on soldier, the other on a civilian hilding a W.S.S.
    - Boys and girls / You can help your Uncle Sam with the war / Save your quarters / Buy War Savings Stamps (Folder 19)
      Uncle Sam holding W.S.S. / holding a young girl and facing a boy
    - Help him win by saving and serving / Buy War Savings Stamps, 1918 (Folder 19)
      Soldier holding hands of boy and girl
    - Saveyour child from autocracy and poverty / Buy War Savings Stamps (Folder 19)
      Child holding arm of Statue of Liberty
    - Save buy for victory / W.S.S. War Savings Stamps issued by the United States Governments / For Sale Here, 1918 (Folder 19)
      Torch of Liberty (seal)
    - "We'll help you to win the war Dad" with War Savings Stamps. / Dedicated to the Boy Scouts of America (Folder 19)
      Soldier and Boy Scout holding book of war stamps
    - We are doing our bit / Help our W.S.S. Drive / Sept 3rd to 13th (Folder 19)
      African-American soldier and brigade attacking German troups
    - For victory / Buy W.S.S. / War Savings Stamps (Folder 19)
      Soldier leading troups in battle
    - W.S.S. enlistment / Important notice! / The President of the United States proclaims Friday, June 28, 1918 National War Savings Day Howard Cheney / Connectuct War Savings Director (Folder 19)
    - Buy W.S.S. at any bank or post office / Franklin's picture recalls his saying "A penny saved is a penny earned.: / On a War Savings Stamp it reminds us that $4.00 saved is $5.00 earned (Folder 19)
      Head of Ben Franklin
    - Joan of Arc saved France / Women of America / Save your country / Buy War Savings Stamps, 1918-01-29 (Folder 19)
      Joan of Arc
    - Save and Invest in the Safest / Simplest / Security / Buy W.S.S. / Jan 1, 1918 Jan 1 1923 / $4.12 will equal $5.00 (Folder 19)
      Seal with Torch of Liberty
    - Keep him free / Buy War Savings Stamps (Folder 19)
      American eagle / war planes
    - Don't think of giving gold pieces this Christmas / Let your Christmas gifts win the war / War Savings Stamps / Issued by the United States Government!, 1918-06-23 (Folder 19)
      Torch of Liberty (Seal)
    - They give their lives / Do you lend your savings? (Folder 19)
      Hill with crosses
    - I am telling you / On June 28th I expect you / To enlist in the army of / War Savings to back up my / Army of fighters / W.S.S. Enlistment (Folder 19)
    - Share in the victory / Save for yuour country / Save for yourself / Buy War Savings Stamps (Folder 19)
      Winged Victory carrying palm leaf and a sword
    - This couldn't happen / Just because our boys have won the war they're not running away now in order to get home for Christmas. Instead thy're marching right ahead into Germany. / But are you running away? Keep your War Savings Stamps! (Folder 19)
      Signpost America / Germany: Most soldiers marching into Germany; a few retreating to America
    - Help them / Keep your war savings pledge (Folder 19)
      Soldiers with machine gun, $5.00 War Savings Stamps as ammunition
    - Help us make it hot for the Kaiser / Buy your stamps here now and see the thermometer go up / An idle Quarter is a slacker quarter / Invest in thrift stamps now and save some lad's life in no man's land (Folder 19)
      Wall Thermometer
    - June 28th is National War Savings Day / Pledge youself to sae nad buy / War Savings Stamps / That There may be more / Money, labor, and materials / to provide for those who fight for you (Folder 19)
      Eagle, torchof Liberty / NYC in background (rust color)
    - One destroyer might have prevented this/You can turn the trick/Help beat the building schedule/This means you (Folder 20)
      sinking battleship/men in lifeboats
- Series III: Patriotic Appeals, 3
  Series III: Patriotic Appeals, includes posters produced by the government and a variety of state civilian associations encouraging farmers, workers, women, and children to engage in war work and support their country's war effort. Among those encouraging general patriotism are warning messages to watch for spies, avoid rumors and avoid "war talk."
  - Subseries III.1: Patriotic Appeals to Workers, Farmers, Miners etc., 16
    - The Past is Behind Us/The Future is Ahead/Let Us All Strive to Make the Future/Better and Brighter/Than the Past Ever Was., 1918 (Folder 20)
      soldier + farmer shaking hands
    - Send her off to/The war zone/Ahead of schedule/To guard our/Boys on the transports/Are you on the job?/Your bit counts don't waste it (Folder 20)
      workman waving goodbye to battleship
    - A destroyer a day/Keeps the subs away/Beat the building schedule/Sink the submarines (Folder 20)
      destroyer on high seas
    - The employer/And employee/Have/A mutual/Interest in/Increasing production (Folder 20)
    - The difficulties of peace are as great/As the difficulties of war/"An admirable spirit of selfsacrifice, patriotic devotion and community action guided us during the war. We shall need all these now..If we are to accomplish the 1st tasks of peace"WW (Folder 20)
      photo of Woodrow Wilson
    - The sensible course/Is to secure the good/Which is within our/Grasp and not by reaching out too far/ For the unattainable/A full day's work/By the great/Majority of adults is/Necessary for progress and prosperity. David Houston, Society of Agriculture (Folder 20)
    - Hercules powders/A surprise party, 1919 (Folder 20)
      soldier returning home/dogs welcoming him
    - One of the old/Ideals of the Republic/Was that the limit of /Striving for success/Was the limit of capacity and endurance/The real evil/We arec onfronting today/Is the high cost of leisure"Thomas R. Marshall, VicePresident of the U.S. (Folder 20)